blogpulse.com 2005-12-14

# Intelliseek - Privacy Policy - Marketing Intelligence, Business Intelligence, Lead Generation

  | INTELLISEEK  
Privacy Policy

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for [http://www.intelliseek.com](http://www.intelliseek.com/). If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you may contact Intelliseek by sending us an [e-mail](javascript:MakeMail\('privacy-concerns'\)). This Privacy Policy applies to information that is collected on [http://www.intelliseek.com](http://www.intelliseek.com/). 

The Intelliseek Web site also contains links to other Web sites; please note that when you click on one of these links, you are connecting to another Web site. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites as their privacy policy may differ from ours.

You can expect to be notified of: 

  1. What Personally Identifiable Information of yours is collected?
  2. What organization is collecting the information?
  3. How is the information used?
  4. With whom the information may be shared?
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of the information? 
  6. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information? 
  7. What kinds of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under the company's control?
  8. Who does Intelliseek use to serve ads on its website? 

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to Intelliseek's [Support Services department.](javascript:MakeMail\('privacy-concerns'\))

Privacy Philosophy 

The Internet is rapidly changing the way all of us communicate and interact with each other. While the Internet allows each of us access to a greater array of information and services than has ever been available, these new online activities do raise new challenges, such as the privacy issues addressed in this policy. Intelliseek is committed to working with public policy organizations, industry groups, and government institutions to understand and address these challenges as they arise. But most importantly, having a relationship with our customers that is founded on trust, is not only good manners, it is also good business. Any [feedback](javascript:MakeMail\('infoemail'\)) you'd like to provide to help us better meet your expectations in this arena is welcomed. 

**Our Commitments to You**

Intelliseek wants to make your online experience satisfying and safe. Our data collection policies allow you to choose how much information to provide to us, and to control how we use that information. Our goal is to provide you with a personalized, robust and productive online experience while allowing you to control your privacy. 

Intelliseek collects information online primarily to make it easier and more rewarding for you to use our services. Depending on the service you are accessing, you could be asked at various times to provide information such as your name, e-mail address, or information about what you like and do not like. On other occasions such as when we provide items for purchase online, we may request your credit card number to conclude the transaction, or your mailing address to ensure proper delivery. We request this information to provide our strongest value to you — a personalized online experience. Customers who personalize our service come back more often — and it's the customers that visit us often who make us successful — so we do everything we can to make Intelliseek your service and to give you just the content you want. Information collected online is often defined as being either anonymous or personally identifiable: 

  1. **Anonymous Information** refers to information that cannot be tied back to a specific individual. For instance, we may know that 10,000 people visit this Privacy Policy today, but we do not necessarily know their names, where they live, or their date of birth. What we collect from transactions, such as this, constitutes anonymous information, much like how your hometown's bus service knows how many people take a given route — but doesn't necessarily know specifically who those people are. Many of the individuals who access our services choose not to register with Intelliseek, and therefore those individuals are anonymous to us and the data we collect is similarly anonymous information. 

  2. **Personally Identifiable Information** refers to information that tells us specifically who you are, such as your name, phone number, or postal address. In many cases we ask for this information to provide you with enhanced services. Examples of the use of such information would include shipping products purchased from Intelliseek . We hope that, like many of our customers, you will find it beneficial to judiciously provide Personally Identifiable Information to Intelliseek so that we may provide more valuable free content, information and products to you, on a timely basis. The amount of Personally Identifiable Information that you choose to disclose to Intelliseek is completely up to you. The only way we know something about you personally is if you register with Intelliseek or enter one of our Intelliseek sweepstakes. In other words, we will know Personally Identifiable Information about you only if you choose to provide this type of information to us. 

**What Personally Identifiable Information of yours is collected?**

In our effort to provide personalization and opportunities for prizes and services, we may at times ask you to submit information such as your Name or e-mail address, or to share your interests and hobbies with us. You never have to answer these questions, and you can decline this exchange of information on any site on the Internet — not just ours — at any time. 

However, if should you choose to withhold requested information, we may not be able to provide you with some of the services dependent upon the collection of this information, such as updated Intelligent Agents, the latest product releases, a sweepstakes entry, or the purchase and shipment of products and prizes.. If you are an Intelliseek BullsEye Pro customer, you are electing to use a paid product that requires you to supply certain information to establish the shipping information. For instance, your name, address, phone number, and potentially your credit card number must be provided to purchase the product. 

When you surf the Internet, your Internet browser (such as Netscape Navigator® or Microsoft Internet Explorer) automatically transmits some information to Intelliseek every time you access content on one of our sites. Examples of such information include the Universal Resource Locator (URL) of the Web page you were just on (known as the "Referer"), the IP (or Internet Protocol) address of the computer you are using, or the browser version you are using to access our site. All of this information is collected by Intelliseek servers and is used to help improve our offerings to you. For instance, from this information we determined that a very few of our customers use older browser versions. Because of this we recently decided to enhance the quality of content available to all of our customers by using the advanced features of HTML that cannot be accessed from those older browser versions. All of the information that is automatically submitted to us by your browser is considered Anonymous Information. 

To enable many of the features available within Intelliseek, we will assign "cookies" to your Internet browser (such as Netscape Navigator or Microsoft Internet Explorer). A cookie is a small text file that contains a unique identification number stored on your computer. Cookies by themselves cannot be used to find out the identity of any user. This unique identification number automatically identifies your browser — but not you — to our computers whenever you interact on one of our Internet domains using that browser. When you visit our site, a cookie in effect says to our server computers "Hello, I'm browser #655. What do you do just for me?" Every Web page that you access that includes advertising or content served from Intelliseek will have the contents of your cookie reported in our server logs. But only when you agree to provide Personally Identifiable Information directly to an Intelliseek branded service, such as through registration, will we be able to know anything about you other than the random number that our server computers originally assign to your browser. 

There is a lot of confusion about cookies, how they are used, and what they can do. Cookies only contain information that the server computer "knew" in the first place, and can only be read by the serving domain that placed them. For instance, Yahoo! utilizes cookies, but Intelliseek's servers can't read their contents nor can Yahoo!'s servers read ours. Cookies are an essential part of how the Internet works today, and allow server computers to recognize your computer's browser when you return. If you have ever gone to a Web page that automatically provides personalized content, or remembers the preferences you set in previous use, without you having to "sign in," such as your own stock portfolio, this is almost certainly being accomplished with a cookie. Since cookies are only text files, they cannot "run" on your computer and have no ability to search your computer for other information, or transmit it to anyone. Cookies are part of the technology implemented by your Web browser. But don't just take our word for it — read what the companies who wrote the browsers have to say! 

**What organization is collecting the information?**

The data you provide in any Intelliseek domain or with any Intelliseek product, is collected by the Intelliseek Corporation with its headquarters at 1128 Main Street, Fourth Floor, Cincinnati, OH 45202—7236. 

**How is the information used?**

The majority of the services that are provided for free through Intelliseek are supported by banner advertising revenues or through other sponsorships. Our ability to provide enhanced services and content to our customers is dependent on our ability to provide venues for our advertisers, advertising and promotion partners or business partners (referred to collectively as "Partner" or "Partners") that reach specific demographic segments of our customer base. Generally, Partners have little interest in reaching a specific customer of our services — and as a matter of policy we provide no mechanism for Partner to reach you or any other specific customer unless you request that contact. Instead, our Partners have the need to reach general collection of customers who share common demographic characteristics such as a specific gender or age range. 

For instance, certain products are more often purchased by women then by men and therefore when advertising those products, in this example, the Partner would prefer to target their messages just to women. The better job Intelliseek does in providing a mechanism for Partners to reach specific sub—segments of our users, the more revenue we can generate from advertising and that ultimately is what allows you, the consumer, to get to the wealth of new technologies and free content from Intelliseek's various services. Importantly, at no time, is your Personally Identifiable Information used to determine what advertising you receive nor do we use it to determine what type of advertising any other customer of Intelliseek will receive.

Below is a description of the uses of the information that we collect and how our visitors and advertisers Partners benefit from these actions: 

  1. We pay attention to what our customers do and do not use on our service, and modify our content and technology appropriately.

  2. We match the patterns of usage that our consumers exhibit during use of our products or Web sites where we serve advertising to create "imputed profiles" about our anonymous customers. The creation of an imputed profile allows Intelliseek to statistically model the demographic characteristics of an otherwise anonymous customer, without ever knowing that anonymous customer's name or any other Personally Identifiable Information about them. These imputed profiles are used to target advertising — primarily banners — to those anonymous customers, both on Intelliseek domains. Through the use of imputed profiles, Intelliseek can surface advertising to our customers that is more likely to be for products they would want, and sell that advertising in the marketplace for a higher price. This is essential to our ability to provide access to state of the art technologies and high quality content to our customers for free. Intelliseek never matches "Who you are" with "Where you've been" on the Internet because we do not use personal data characteristics such as your name, address or phone number to create these imputed profiles but rather use primary demographic characteristics such as your age or gender. Finally, imputed profiles present no privacy risk to our customers because they are worthless to third parties; since any potential third party would be unable to read the cookies that we set on our domains, only Intelliseek can create value from these imputed profiles. 

  3. We provide advertisements that support our customers' specific requests for information through Keyword searches and editorial content. Do a search on "cars," for instance, and you might see a banner advertisement from an automobile company. 

  4. We develop summary reports for our Partners. An example of a summary report might be "12,000 people clicked on Advertisement 'X' today, and of those people, 35% had previously indicated they had an interest in sports." Our Partners, who make it possible for you to use Intelliseek for free, need this information to determine how effective their advertising investments are. We never tell our Partners who in particular (with name, address or any such identifiable information) it was that saw or clicked on their advertisements, unless you have specifically told us it is acceptable to do so. 

  5. If you enter a sweepstakes or a contest, we'll use the information you supplied to contact you. We'll probably also congratulate you!

  6. We will send registrants of Intelliseek outbound e-mail communications on information we think they will find useful, including information about new products and services from selected Partners. It is our policy to never send messages to Members who have asked us not to do so, either at initial registration or later through an unsubscribe process. In every e-mail from any company or Web site of Intelliseek, we intend to remind you of your option to change your preferences regarding receipt of future e-mail communications

  7. Finally, if we believe that Intelliseek property or an individual's safety or security is at risk, we will disclose this information to proper court or law enforcement agencies. 

Please note, if we are going to use your Personally Identifiable Information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not to allow us to use your information in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post the notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

**With whom the information may be shared?**

If you are providing us Personally Identifiable Information, it will only be used within Intelliseek Internet domains unless you choose to allow third party data sharing (by opting in for such distribution during the registration process). Should you choose to provide your information to third parties, Intelliseek will share aspects of your information with our valued Partners. Some of these transactions will include financial payment to Intelliseek for the information provided but are only undertaken with companies whose privacy practices are consistent with the principles established within this policy and with whom Intelliseek believes that a product that truly benefits our customers can be promoted. Our Partners help contribute towards many of the free services available from Intelliseek 

Although unlikely, Intelliseek may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide personally Identifiable Information to the appropriate governmental authorities. If requested by law enforcement or judicial authorities, we will provide this information upon receipt of the appropriate documentation. 

Other companies that place advertising on our site, products or services may collect information about you when you view or click on their advertising or content through the use of cookies (using the same techniques as described above). Due to the way the Internet technically operates, we cannot control this collection of information — but we can control which companies are allowed to place such advertising on our site, products or services. 

As the consumer you should contact these advertisers or content providers that place information on Intelliseek directly if you have any questions about their use of the information they potentially collect. It should be noted that anyone placing advertising on our Web sites or products could only collect Anonymous Information about you unless you actively provide Personally Identifiable Information directly to them. For a complete description of our advertisement provider's privacy Statement, please visit <http://www.doubleclick.net/privacy_policy/>. 

Finally, Intelliseek does not control the information collection and distribution policies on Internet domains other than those Intelliseek Internet domains that are part of Intelliseek.

**What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of the information?**

Intelliseek does offer you the ability to control the e-mail communications we make to you. It is our intention to give you as much control over our relationship as possible. 

First, as mentioned earlier, the consumer always has the final word on whether Intelliseek—or any Internet company—knows who you are. It is your choice to share Personally Identifiable Information with Intelliseek and we encourage you to consider only sharing information with any site on the Internet if you receive true value in exchange for that information transfer and if you respect the privacy practices of the firm. 

If you do choose to share Personally Identifiable Information with Intelliseek, you can control whether we contact you or share the information with third parties, either through declarations you make at the time you share information with us, or through updates to your information by [contacting us](javascript:MakeMail\('support'\)). Intelliseek will always give you a chance to unsubscribe to any e-mail communication from us—clear directions for doing so will appear in any e-mail message we send to you. 

Co-Branding partnerships provide an ASP solution to our clients by customizing Intelliseek products to reflect the client's brand identity. At times, Intelliseek may enter into Co-Branding arrangements with other companies, and if so, an opt-in question may be present for contact from these firms as well. 

Their opt-out features are specific to each organization, but you should never receive e-mail from these organizations unless you have indicated that it is acceptable. All e-mail from Intelliseek, or from Intelliseek co—brand partners who gain your permission to send you commercial e-mail, will include an opportunity to opt out of future communications. 

Intelliseek does reserve the right to send one-time registration confirmation e-mail, and Agent Update messages to its customers to inform them of specific changes that may impact their ability to use a service they have previously signed up for, regardless of e-mail contact opt-in status. An example of an Agent Update message would be notification of the availability of new or modified agents. And finally, we also reserve the right to contact you if compelled to do so as part of a legal proceeding or if there has been a violation of our Terms of Service. Intelliseek is retaining these rights because in limited cases we feel that we may need the right to contact you as a matter of law or regarding matters, which will be important to you. These rights do not allow us to contact you to market a new or existing service if you have asked us not to do so, and issuance of these types of communications are rare. 

**How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information**

Intelliseek believes strongly in providing you with the ability to edit the personal information that you have provided to us. To update the information retained about you, or to deactivate your account, please contact us via [e-mail](javascript:MakeMail\('support'\)).

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post the notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

**What kinds of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under the company's control?**

Security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under the company's control. Intelliseek operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewalls and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary, and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers. Even your registration account password is encrypted before it is sent to our computers—no one in the company could tell you what your password is even if you asked! Any other particularly sensitive information, such as a customer's credit card number collected for a commerce transaction, is also encrypted prior to transmission. 

You, the consumer, are ultimately responsible for the security of your registration id. 

**Who does Intelliseek use to serve ads on its website?**

Our Web sites use reputable third parties to serve the advertisements that you see on the pages of our Web site. If you would like to know more about the information gathering practices and "opt-out" procedures of our third party ad servers, [click here](http://www.doubleclick.net/privacy_policy/).

|    
---|---|---
